Brandon Smeltzer

+1 734 845 8216



brandon.m.smeltzer@ gmail.com



Berrien Springs (MI)



linkedin.com/in/ brandonsmeltzer456



SKILLS

Critical Thinking

Analytics

Negotiation

Adaptability

Problem Solving

Attention to Detail

Team Management

Continuous Learning

Microsoft Suite

Epic EMR

EDUCATION

DOCTORATE OF OSTEOPATHIC MEDICINE Medicine Lake Erie College of Osteopathic Medicine 2013 - 2017

> BACHELOR'S DEGREE Spanish University of Michigan 2004 - 2010

PROFILE

Up until this point, my professional career has focused on honing skills and knowledge as a physician. This has been accomplished through the avenues of education, research and clinical experience. I have developed incredible communication skills through relationships with patients, clinical staff and other physicians.

EXPERIENCE

RESIDENT PHYSICIAN

Spectrum Health | Saint Joseph, MI | 2020 - 2021

Meet with patients to discuss and differentiate priority and pathology of disease processes. Meet with staff regarding disease management and follow-up. Review and procure necessary equipment for planned daily procedures. Assess and resolve potential scheduling conflicts within daily patient census.

- Create simplified processes to enhance patient compliance.
- Coordinate & improve operations of the healthcare team.
- Provide accurate coding for proper billing.
- Create concise presentations for medical education.

RESIDENT PHYSICIAN

Mercy Health | Youngstown, OH | 2017 - 2018

Advise patients, create orders and write for necessary medications through Epic inbox functions. Review Inpatient census to assess for disposition and upcoming procedures. Consult with other physicians to obtain appropriate diagnosis and disease management. Contact patients regarding recent laboratory and imaging results.

- Analyze, trend and forecast data to formulate an accurate diagnosis.
- Generate & validate appropriate disease management.
- Report necessary data to leadership to optimize care strategy.
- Communicate & document individual assessment and plan.

RESEARCH ASSISTANT

Northwestern University | Chicago, IL | 2012 - 2013

Perform protocols to isolate and analyze all RNA, DNA and protein samples. Conduct electrocardiograms and induce atrial fibrillation within all canine cardiac models. Collect and analyze ECG signals to determine statistical significance utilizing Excel.